Guide to the Rice University Black Student Association records, 1972-2016 UA 370
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Black Student Association records
1972-2016
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 370
1.5 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
This collection consists of correspondence, minutes, and memorabilia created by the Black Students' Union and the Black Student Association.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Catherine E. Clack donated materials in 2012. Renita King and Akilah Mance donated materials in 2016.
Accruals
Additional materials are expected for this collection.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of items created by the Black Students' Union and the Black Student Association, more specifically, minutes, histories, correspondence, and memorabilia.
Biographical / Historical
Founded at Rice University in the early 1970s, the Black Students' Union created a safe, welcoming environment for black students at Rice.
Starting in 1972, the Black Students' Union worked with the administration to start a B.S.U. Center. This morphed into the Office of Multicultural Affairs, which housed the center.
By 1989, the Black Student Association provided another club for black students on campus. In the mid 1990s, the Black Students' Union combined with the Black Student Association.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; African Americans
Document Types
memorabilia
- Series I: Alphabetical files
  - "Black Profile", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Black Students' Union Center, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Constitution, 2013/2014 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Events, 2011, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Funding, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History of Black Students at Rice, ca. 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Membership Policy, 2013/2014 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 2013/2014 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II: Memorabilia
  - Graduation stole, 2000s (Box 2)
  - 50 Years of Black Undergraduate Life T-shirt, 2016 (Box 2)
  - Black Student Union blue T-shirt, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Harambe: Working Together in Unity T-shirt, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Black Student Association T-shirt, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Black Student Association ARUBA T-shirt, n.d. (Box 2)